Finding Aid for Center for Chinese Studies (University of Michigan) Publications, 1969-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Center for Chinese Studies (University of Michigan) publications 1969-2006 1983-1997
University of Michigan. Center for Chinese Studies.
0.4 linear ft.
9742 Bimu C26 2
Miscellaneous Center for Chinese Studies newsletters, student publications, calendars, bibliographies, and brochures. Also contains a set of monographs produced in various series by the center.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit.
The record group is open without restriction.
See history in finding aid for Center for Chinese Studies (Unveristy of Michigan)
The Publications series (0.4 linear ft.) is divided into two subseries: Unit Publications and Student Publications.
The Unit Publications subseries includes bibliographies, publications catalogs, and calendars and flyers describing the brown bag lunch series and the Chinese film series. This subseries also contains newsletters such as Center for Chinese Studies and Alumni News. The Center for Chinese Studies cooperated with the Center for Japanese Studies to produce the newsletters CCS-CJS News, CCS-CJS News Update, and the East Asian Studies Newsletter.
The Student Publications subseries includes three titles from the late 1960s and early 1970s. Ta Tzu Pao was first published in 1969 and continued to be published monthly during the academic year. Unfortunately, the Bentley Library does not hold a complete run of this publication. It ceased publication in 1970. The Dodder was published in 1970. The title was changed to Voices in 1971. A fourth publication entitled Spring-Autumn Papers was a graduate student journal published in 1979 and 1980.
Most of these unit and student publications are in English, though there are occasional passages in Chinese.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Center for Chinese Studies.; University of Michigan. Center for Japanese Studies.; Newsletters.; Student publications.; Bibliographies.; Brochures.; Calendars.; Michigan abstracts of Chinese and Japanese works on Chinese history.; Michigan classics in Chinese studies.; Michigan monographs in Chinese studies.; Michigan papers in Chinese studies.; Occasional papers (University of Michigan. Center for Chinese Studies); Science, medicine, and technology in East Asia.; CCS-CJS news.; CCS-CJS news update.; Dodder.; Ta tzu pao.; Voices.
- Publications
  - Unit Publications
    - Bibliographies
      - Guide to Current Research on East Asia, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Calendars
      - Brown Bag Lecture Series, 1990-2002 (Box 1)
      - Calendar of Events, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
      - Chinese Film Series, 1991-1997 (Box 1)
    - Catalogs
      - Publications Catalogs, 1988-1990 (Box 1)
    - Flyers
      - Brown Bag Lecture Series, 1989-1992, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Chinese Film Series, 1991-2005 (Box 1)
      - Conferences and Lectures, 1992-2004, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Handbooks
      - Course description handbook, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - Alumni News, 1983 (Box 1)
      - Center for Chinese Studies, 1974-1978, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - CCS news, 1978/1979 (Box 1)
      - CCS-CJS News, 1979-1989, 11 folders (Box 1)
      - CCS-CJS News Update, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
      - East Asian Studies Newsletter, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Other
      - Chinese and Japanese studies at the University of Michigan, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Student Publications
    - Dodder, 1970 [Precedes Voices ] (Box 1)
    - Spring-Autumn Papers
      - 1979 vol. 1, no. 1 (Box 1)
      - 1980 vol. 2, no. 1 (Box 1)
    - Ta Tzu Pao, 1969-1970 (3 folders] (Box 1)
    - Voices, 1971 [Supersedes Dodder ] (Box 1)